Jeffrey Fonseca — Resume

■ jeff.fonseca777 [at] gmail.com • **J** +1-573-***-**** Github G: moonpiedumplings • Website/ moonpiedumplings.github.io

Summary

Avid user of Linux Δ and related technologies for 6 years, intimately familiar with them through personal projects, daily usage, and teaching others. Proficient in both operations, and technical writing/documentation.

I have a site where I document all my work, write about tech, and post guides for other to use: moonpiedumplings.github.io

Professional Experience

Internship at Cirrascale Cloud

- Installed and configured PFSense **①** on Proxmox
- Used packer to automate creation of a MAAS image that deploys Proxmox
- Documented K3's kubernetes, vcluster, and Kata-containers on Nvidia GPU's for machine learning operations
- Assisted in building physical servers 🗮, including doing tasks like installing storage 🖨, memory 🕮, or Nvidia GPU's

Date: 7/10/2023 - 8/26/2023

Date: Fall 2023 to Ongoing

Date: 2016 - 2022

WUOTT — Behevioral Health Clinic

- General helpdesk and tech support
- Deployed Meshcentral on an Ubuntu VPS using Docker Compose vs o I could access, manage, and troubleshoot Windows **■** devices remotely

Independent Organizations

President of Layer 8 Cybersecurity Club at Cal State Northridge

CSUN competes in a cybersecurity competition, CCDC. Much of the work here is for that.

- Automated firewalls, backups, password shuffling and container management via Ansible
- Designed a reproducible development environment for Linux △, Windows ■, and Mac using Nix ♣
- Introduced and taught people Linux Δ , concepts, and related software \clubsuit , \gt __, N, \leftrightharpoons , O, \rightleftarrows Did regular presentations, every Monday, on various cybersecurity, cloud, and devops topics
- Completed multiple NICE challenges, involving Linux Δ , terminal $\mathbf{\lambda}_{-}$, and database $\mathbf{\Xi}$ management. Wrote 5 Writeups to assist my teammates.
- Led the CČDC team to regionals as the Linux team lead, taking 7th out of 27 teams

Personal/Educational Projects

- Deployed a Minecraft & server using Podman to an Oracle Cloud VPS
- Built CI/CD Pipelines using GitHub Actions and Docker , to deploy to an AWS EC2 VPS, for a class project for AP CSP. Over 40 students utilized my pipelines for auto deployment
- Dockerized Node.js ** Python *, and Java * applications
- Wrote technical documentation to assist students and teachers in AP CSP (E.g. duckdns)
- Deployed Kasmweb on a highly performance optimized Ubuntu **②** VPS
- Deployed a point to site Wireguard VPN connection between my router and a VPS
- Installed OpenStack on Rocky Stinux Using Kolla-Ansible
- Deployed a Kubernetes cluster using FLuxCD (GitOps)
- Deployed Incus (Proxmox/ESXi alternative) with Single Sign on and Fine Grained Authentication to control what resources invited users had access to

Current personal projects can be found on my website, where I document my work as go. I make it a point to pick challenges beyond my current ability. I don't always succeed, but I always grow in the process.

Education

The items in this section are in chronological order, from things I did first to things I did most recently.

- Cal State Northridge Computer Science BS expected graduation 05/27
 - ☑ Introduction to Algorithms and Programming (COMP 110/L) &
 - ☑ Data Structures in Java (COMP 182/L) 🗐
 - ⊠ Calculus 2 (CALC 150B)
 - ⊠ Computer Architecture (COMP 122)
 - ☑ Discrete Structures (COMP 256)

^{&#}x27;\n* Managed a Wordpress site\n* Managed an email server\n'